CHAS HUGGINS

(631) 983-7235 hugginsc10@gmail.com PORTFOLIO GITHUB LINKEDIN

SKILLS Algorithms, Data Structures, JavaScript, Ruby, Python, React / Redux, Node.js, Express, GraphQL, Ruby on Rails, Docker

PROJECTS

JOB HARMONY (React / Redux, NodeJS / Express, MongoDB)

live | github

An innovative application that is used by employers and job seekers in order to anonymously help experienced professionals find a job and employers to find outstanding employees

- Utilized JSON Web Token and BCrypt for the backend user auth.
- Used faker to seed a large database of occupations and job listings in development and testing in order to create the necessary API endpoints for a user to have control over search preferences.
- Created multiple component animations with CSS3, HTML5 and JavaScript.

SAVE A STRAY (React / Apollo, NodeJS / Express, MongoDB, GraphQL)

live | github

An application that connects animal shelters with adopters with the purpose of creating a convenient way for animals to be rescued.

- Uses OAuth with JWT in order to get user data and creating a convenient way for our users to sign in.
- Utilizes Google Maps API to generate a map of nearby animal shelters by users location generated by location data.
- Utilizes GraphQL for Apollo to query the MongoDB database.
- Implemented payment API for users or guests to donate directly to shelters.

SPACE TETRIS (HTML5, JavaScript, NodeJS / Express)

live | github

A new spin on the 1984 classic arcade game developed using HTML5 and JavaScript.

- Utilized HTML5 Canvas to create the Tetromino board and CSS to style and add the space themed background.
- Used a grid to account for Tetromino collisions and stacked the Tetromino's by merging them to the grid.
- Used EventListeners for keyboard and button controls.
- Created a simple NodeJS / Express Server for deployment to Heroku and for future features.

EXPERIENCE

Managing Partner

Vacheron Holdings LLC Jan 2019 - Present

- Consulted over 15 restaurants in the New York Metropolitan area resulting in an average increase in profit of 33%.
- Started a real estate investment arm that has acquired multiple buildings that are being renovated to be used in 1Q2020 with a projection of an annualized 17% ROI over 10 years.
- Consulted e-commerce companies helping them grow their revenue and increase both their organic and paid reach.

Quantitative Trader

Vacheron Capital LLC Oct 2017 - Present

- Price derivatives and execute trades using proprietary software developed using Python.
- Mitigate overall portfolio risk by seeking correlations between different assets.
- Actively testing new strategies using alternative data, such as social media and web traffic.

EDUCATION

Web Development - *App Academy* | *Winter 2019* **B.Sc Accounting / Economics -** *The Citadel* | 2006 - 2010